good afternoon welcome to ask JDK
下午好，欢迎问一下JDK
architects here we are again I'm mark
建筑师在这里，我们再次成为我的标志
Reinhold I am joined by John Rose Bryan
Reinhold我和John Rose Bryan一起加入
gets Alex Buckley I work on everything
让亚历克斯·巴克利我做所有的事情
John works mainly on the VM Bryan and
约翰主要从事VM Bryan和
Alex work on on the language and how it
亚历克斯致力于语言及其发展
looks after the specifications so this
照顾规格，所以这
that there's hardly any presentation
几乎没有介绍
here you'll note this is from 2016
在这里您会注意到这是从2016年开始的
because sorry I was busy with some other
因为对不起，我正忙于其他一些事情
slides today and didn't have time to
今天幻灯片，没有时间
update it they're only they're only two
更新它们只是他们只有两个
other slides in this deck one is that
这个甲板上的其他幻灯片之一是
one yes we still work for work the other
一个是，我们仍然为工作而工作
is well this is QA so we have a mic up
很好，这是质量检查，所以我们有麦克风了
here we have a mic up here you can come
这里我们有麦克风，你可以来
use if you're shy you could you could
如果您害羞，请使用
tweet at me and maybe I'll repeat your
向我发推文，也许我会重复你的
question maybe I won't I have had it can
问题也许我不会拥有
exercise editorial control so have at it
行使编辑控制权
we've got 44 minutes or so for QA any
我们有44分钟左右的质量检查时间
question you everyone asked doesn't mean
大家问的问题并不意味着
we will necessarily answer them so
我们一定会回答他们
Mike's right up here or if somebody
迈克在这里或有人
wants to run it around and do that drop
想跑来跑去掉
you can do that too
你也能做到
so if I've got a program I'm running in
所以如果我有一个正在运行的程序
my JVM and I know what meta space
我的JVM，我知道什么元空间
setting I want I know what heat setting
我想知道什么设定
I want I've found it's incredibly
我想我已经找到了
difficult to figure out how much memory
很难找出多少内存
on the machine or the VM is going to be
在机器上或虚拟机将
needed and I was wondering I've seen a
需要，我想知道我已经看到了
little bit about some sort of support
关于某种支持的一点点
for that with the Java 9 and the
为此，使用Java 9和
available memory but is there a good way
可用内存，但是有一个好方法
to figure that out or is that really
弄清楚还是真的
just a run it a lot and measure until it
只是大量运行并测量直到
gets down but the nature of complex
下来但复杂的本质
dynamic systems I love John's grimace
动态系统我爱约翰的鬼脸
somebody get a picture that we do we we
有人得到一张照片，我们做到了我们
we give you the controls because we
我们给您控件，因为我们
don't know how to drive them
不知道怎么开车
automatically I think that's the short
我认为这很短
answer
回答
the longer answer is we have some very
更长的答案是我们有一些非常
smart people in the storage management
聪明的人在存储管理中
group who worry about this stuff all the
那些担心这些东西的小组
time and you know they they they're
时间，你知道他们他们是
trying they're trying to figure this out
试图他们试图弄清楚这一点
and make it better over time the the
并随着时间的推移变得更好
problem of the last several years has
最近几年的问题
been in Layton sees max latency and
来过雷顿（Layton）的人看到最大延迟
we've gotten a good handle on that you
我们已经很好地处理了你
know you if you if you squeeze one
如果你挤一个就知道你
parameter or the other ones pop out of
参数或其他参数弹出
control and I suppose now that we're
控制，我想现在我们
getting into clustered and and stacked
进入群集和堆叠
containers running on you know in small
在您身上运行的容器很小
spaces constrained spaces we need to
空间限制我们需要的空间
look again at at memory limitations and
再看一下内存限制和
and you know with with the rapid
你知道与快速
build-out of cloud infrastructure Java
建立云基础架构Java
is going on that ship big time where
在那艘大船上航行
we're looking at ways to make the the VM
我们正在寻找制作虚拟机的方法
have more predictable memory
有更多可预测的记忆
requirements but I would say it's early
要求，但我会说还早
days on that and best thing to do would
天，最好的事情是
be to have the community tell us what
让社区告诉我们什么
their best practices are so that and
他们的最佳做法是
tell us if it's if it's so easy that
告诉我们是否很简单
that even a machine even a robot could
即使是机器甚至是机器人都可以
do it then maybe we want our robot to do
然后做，也许我们希望我们的机器人去做
it for you but we have we have special
它给你，但我们有我们特别
insight into some algorithms of how to
深入了解如何
manage memory and keep it keep it
管理内存并保留它
limited in size but the special
大小有限，但特殊
knowledge does not give us the best an
知识不能给我们最好的
idea of best practices for the actual
实际最佳做法的想法
applications out there in the wild so
野外的应用程序，所以
I'm afraid I have to punt that question
恐怕我不得不提出这个问题
back to this audience fair enough
回到这个听众足够公平
Thanks
谢谢
I have a question for versioning for
我有一个版本问题
next version wouldn't be a better to add
下一个版本将不会更好
some marker of great big feature such as
一些伟大功能的标记，例如
when we when you add value types it will
当我们添加值类型时，
be say 10.20 dot 3 and now we will have
假设10.20点3，现在我们将有
nine dot 18 3 can I ask the question in
九点18 3我可以问这个问题吗
return who wants to spend the next 40
返回谁想花下40
minutes talking about version schemes
会议纪要谈论版本方案
yeah didn't think so
是的，我不这么认为
I mean sorry it's this enormous bike
我的意思是抱歉，这是一辆巨大的自行车
shed we could spend all day on it there
棚子，我们可以在那里呆一整天
are lots of factors to be to be
有很多因素要成为
considered we'll be having a no doubt
认为我们毫无疑问
vigorous discussion of this in within
内部对此进行了激烈的讨论
openjdk when the JT the new JDK project
openjdk当JT新建JDK项目时
is approved so if you care deeply about
被批准，所以如果您很在意
it I encourage you to participate in
我鼓励你参加
that but as I just I don't honestly
那样，但我只是不诚实
think it'd be a productive use of the
认为这将对
time of all the people in this room is
这个房间里所有人的时间是
that I mean is that unfair that's okay
我的意思是那不公平没关系
for a $1 response no no no I was 0.1
对于$ 1的响应否否否我是0.1
beta 1 John well I have a question so
beta 1 John好，我有一个问题，所以
about like I'll report from VM language
就像我将从VM语言报告一样
spec so it's a future of Java memory
规格，因此它是Java内存的未来
model so maybe you can like say
模特，所以也许你可以说
something about it so Jim Jim I'm 9 I
关于它的一些事情，吉姆吉姆，我9岁
may be the future of it
可能是它的未来
so what's planned to be implemented
所以计划要实施什么
needs a future there are some people who
需要未来，有些人
thought about it but I don't know that
考虑了一下，但我不知道
they thought about it very recently you
他们最近才想到
know what yeah there where this is
知道那里是什么
happening is and maybe you've seen him
发生的事，也许你见过他
hints of it is on
它的暗示
JMM working group that Doug Lee leads
道格·李（Doug Lee）领导的JMM工作组
and I would I'll give a couple of
我会给几个
remember the lawyer slide but a couple
记得律师的幻灯片，但有几个
of things that are we're talking about
我们正在谈论的事情
in public are yeah thank you
在公共场合是，谢谢
oh yeah are getting more coherence with
哦，是越来越与
the C++ memory model which is kind of
C ++内存模型
the little brother to the Java memory
Java内存的小兄弟
model Java has powerfully strong and
Java模型具有强大的功能
tight specifications thank you Alex
严格的规格，谢谢亚历克斯
Buckley and others and the memory model
Buckley和其他人以及记忆模型
is one of the places where Java had a
是Java拥有
better spec than any other widely
比其他任何产品都更好的规格
deployed language but now the C++ is
部署的语言，但现在C ++是
growing one we want to make sure that
我们要确保成长
they're they have some coherence
他们有一些连贯性
relative to each other so we're adding
相对于彼此，所以我们要添加
notions like acquire and release but
诸如获取和释放的概念，
it's still no substitute for the base
它仍然无法替代基础
memory model that we have acquired and
我们已经获得的记忆模型
release our behavioral indications of
发布我们的行为指示
what's going on in inside the happens
发生了什么事
before the foundation and that that's
在基金会之前，那是
not going to be changing anytime soon
不会很快改变
will have to be changed with extreme
将不得不极端改变
care one other item though of special
虽然特别照顾另一个项目
interest I would say for the Java memory
我会对Java内存感兴趣
model is we have the special rule for
模式是我们有特殊的规则
final-final fields in object and that
对象中的final-final字段
means that there's a special special
意味着有一个特殊的
guarantee for a safe publication of a
保证安全出版
final final field value in an object and
对象中的最终最终字段值，以及
one thing that Doug thinks that we can
道格认为我们可以做到的一件事
pull off which would be really great if
拉下来，如果真的很棒
possible and it looks possible to me too
可能，对我来说也可能
is extending that guarantee to two
将保证范围扩大到两个
stable fields that aren't necessarily
不一定需要的稳定字段
marked final in all objects so that
在所有对象中标记为最终，以便
would mean that would mean you could
意味着那意味着你可以
have an object that if it's I if the
有一个对象，如果是我，如果
fields are effectively final in other
字段在其他字段中实际上是最终的
words if you don't actually go and have
话，如果你实际上不去拥有
a racing right to the field or a right
竞赛权或田径权
after the constructor exits then for all
在构造函数退出之后，对于所有
intents and purposes your data is as
您的数据的意图和目的
race free as if you had marked the
免费比赛，就好像您已经标记了
fields final that said I it's probably
场决赛说我可能是
pretty hard to use that correctly
很难正确使用它
and again this is the the memory model
再次，这是内存模型
is a concern for library library authors
是图书馆作者的关注点
more than end-users I would say Brian
我要说的不仅仅是最终用户
I'll bet you have something to add to
我敢打赌，您要添加一些内容
that so so there's there's some that
所以有一些
there's been a little bit of progress
有一点进步
you know in the working group as you
你在工作组中知道
know as Don's mentioned it it doesn't a
知道当唐提到它不是
truly impressive panel of experts and
真正令人印象深刻的专家小组和
they've been bashing their collective
他们一直在抨击他们的集体
heads against it for a lot longer than
对抗它的时间比
they planned to and they're still not
他们计划这样做，但他们仍然没有
satisfied that they have something
满意他们有东西
that's better than what we have now but
这比我们现在拥有的要好，但是
they're still bashing their heads
他们仍然在b头
against it so so you know to be
反对，所以你知道是
continued but also there's been some
继续，但也有一些
nice progress in I did find some of the
我确实找到了一些进步
requirements for an updated memory model
更新内存模型的要求
in addition to the coherence with the
除了与
C++ model the of art handles work that
C ++建模艺术负责处理
went into Java ngayon exposes a lot more
进入Java Ngayon暴露了更多
control over the memory coherence
控制内存一致性
requirements so var handles support
要求，因此var处理支持
memory accesses with all of the
所有的内存访问
different access modes you know playing
您知道玩过的不同访问模式
a choir you know one full fence etc so
一个合唱团，你知道一个完整的栅栏等
for bleeding edge adopters who are
适用于
looking to build the fastest libraries
希望建立最快的库
they can there are some new tools that
他们可以有一些新工具
are there for them to to play with
他们在那里玩吗
thanks for bringing the are handles
感谢您带来are句柄
those are a big step forward but they're
这些是向前迈出的一大步，但他们
they also are hard to use correctly yeah
他们也很难正确使用是的
thank you I had a question over here
谢谢，我在这里有一个问题
yeah so I just saw your slide about that
是的，所以我刚刚看到了您的幻灯片
new gussied up switch statement and so
新出现的切换语句等
I'm just trying to understand how with
我只是想了解如何
six months releases how does one develop
六个月发布一个如何发展
features like that so as soon as I saw
这样的功能，所以我一看到
that statement I was thinking about the
我正在考虑的那个陈述
Royal mess that it is in Scala where you
在Scala中，您所处的皇家混乱
know there's 15 different ways of doing
知道有15种不同的方式
the selection and they are all slightly
选择，他们都略
incompatible with each other and clearly
彼此不兼容且明显
that thing had organically grown over
那东西已经有机地生长了
time as yet another graduate student
还是另一个研究生
added another sub feature to it so what
添加了另一个子功能，所以
do you guys do to say okay you know
你们会说好吗
we're gonna roll it out gradually but
我们将逐步推出，但
we're gonna plan it out first what's the
我们要先计划一下
process is and also how does that
过程是，以及如何
process involve the public at large
整个过程都涉及公众
now we have these chaps and jo soares
现在我们有了这些小伙子和乔·苏亚雷斯
and it's all confusing and how is that
一切都令人困惑，那是怎么回事
gonna happen with six months releases so
将在六个月后发布
I managed to cram a lot of stuff in that
我设法塞满了很多东西
question yeah yeah so this there's kind
问题是的，所以这有点
of two aspects to this so the first
这两个方面，所以第一个
question is how do we deal with the
问题是我们如何处理
release frequency which is very
释放频率非常
different from the time scale on which
与时标不同
we've been developing previously and
我们以前一直在开发，
then the other question is how do we
那么另一个问题是我们如何
design features more incrementally
设计功能逐步增加
so those are two separate questions the
所以这是两个独立的问题
first question about the release
有关发布的第一个问题
frequency is actually really easy
频率实际上真的很容易
there's nothing that says we only have
没有什么可以说我们只有
six months to develop a feature it's not
六个月开发一个功能不是
like there's some starting gun that
就像有一些起跑枪
fires like okay start typing and then
像“好吧”一样开始输入然后
you have whatever you have at the end of
你有什么你在结束时
six months ships that's not how it works
六个月的出货时间不正常
right so features are developed in
对，所以功能在
branches there are long-running projects
分支机构有长期运行的项目
surrounding them there are expert groups
他们周围有专家小组
that advise the that advise advise the
劝告劝告
requirements there are people trying out
要求有人在尝试
early access builds and so we're using
抢先体验版，因此我们正在使用
the exact same process as we use to
与我们以前使用的过程完全相同
develop something like lambda but you
开发类似lambda的东西，但是你
know we just you know it's a freerunning
知道我们，只是你知道这是一场自由奔跑
process and OpenJDK you know that you
进程和OpenJDK，您知道您
know is exploring the space now in terms
知道现在正在探索空间
of how you break down a complex feature
如何分解复杂功能
into a number of simpler sub features
进入许多更简单的子功能
the answer is fairly straightforward you
答案很简单
have to design ahead right and so it's
必须提前设计好，所以
if we kind of anticipate well there will
如果我们能很好地期望
be a feature like this and then a
成为这样的功能，然后
feature like this that builds on top of
这样的功能建立在
it and then something this features not
它，然后这个功能没有
ready to ship right ready to ship is not
准备好发货，准备好发货
only do I have a solid design
我只有一个扎实的设计
specification implementation and test
规范实施和测试
week for the future but I have a clear
未来的一周，但我有一个明确的
idea of how it's going to fit into the
如何适应的想法
next three four or five layers of
接下来的三四五层
features built on top of it which
在其之上构建的功能
requires those features to have you know
需要这些功能让您知道
gotten to at least some level where I
至少达到了我的水平
have a design and a prototype and all of
有一个设计和一个原型，所有的
that so it's not like we're gonna throw
这样就不像我们要扔
whatever we had out there every six
每六个我们在那里
months when the bell goes off it's when
铃响了几个月
we feel like this is something that's
我们觉得这是
solid enough and clean enough that it
足够坚固和清洁
can be logically decoupled from teachers
可以在逻辑上与教师脱钩
that would depend on it and we've
这将取决于它，我们已经
developed I think a pretty reasonable
我觉得很合理
sense
感
or you know when when something is
或者你知道什么时候是什么时候
reaching that stage and you know
到达那个阶段，你知道
yes we're probably gonna make some
是的，我们可能会做一些
mistakes but it's still the same people
错误，但仍然是同一个人
that have been moving the platform
一直在移动平台
forward for all these years who have a
这些年来，这些人
deep understanding of what it costs to
深入了解需要花费什么
maintain something for 20 years and how
维持20年，以及如何
features interact with each other and
功能相互影响，并且
the importance of compatibility so I
兼容性的重要性，所以我
don't actually think it's as terrible as
其实并不认为它像
it sounds since I still have the mic
听起来好像我还有麦克风
maybe the switch side sort of threw me
也许开关侧把我扔了
off because when I saw you're talking
因为我看到你在说话
what destructuring I mean there is a lot
我所说的破坏性活动有很多
of stuff that can go wrong in that
可能会出错的东西
particular aspect you know how
你知道的特定方面
comfortable are when do you think this
你什么时候觉得舒服
will actually see this this is not gonna
实际上会看到这不会
be 18 point O 3 right when we're
当我们是18点O 3对
comfortable is the answer right yes it
舒适是答案，对，是的
said so the first feature we showed
说，所以我们展示的第一个功能
today local durable type inference
今天本地持久类型推断
that's already checked in that's done it
已经检查过了
sits on the train it's it's going the
坐在火车上，正要去
other features will come over time in
其他功能将随着时间的流逝而出现
some ways this is hard but in some ways
在某些方面这很难，但在某些方面
it's also frankly liberating right
它也坦率地解放了权利
because you can work on something until
因为你可以做一些事情直到
it's done and then okay what release is
完成，然后好了，什么版本
ready and it goes well I can think of
准备好，一切顺利，我能想到
many language features in se 7 &amp; 8 where
se 7和8中的许多语言功能，其中
as soon as they were shifts it wasn't
他们一上班就不是
that we then realized something that
然后我们意识到一些东西
should have been added as sort of a big
应该已经增加了
user-visible thing but sort of like a
用户可见的东西，但有点像
tiny tweak to type inference an 8 for
进行细微调整以输入8
example where every where it's
例子在哪里
completely additive it's it's just an
完全相加只是一个
extra
额外
it makes the language more open to
它使语言更加开放
support it and to now own if you've only
支持它，现在就拥有，如果您仅
got if you've got 3 years before the
如果您在3年之前
next thing I mean there's no way you can
接下来的事情我是说你不可能
even tell people what what happens it
甚至告诉人们会发生什么
might go into the very first build of
可能会进入
JDK 9 right but you can't tell people
JDK 9对，但是你不能告诉别人
about it and there are lots of these
关于它，还有很多这些
little things lots of little corner
小东西很多小角落
cases basically which you can add
基本上可以添加的案例
completely safely I'm not talking about
完全安全，我不是在说
the difference between a constant
常数之间的差异
pattern and
模式和
the nested pattern and talking about
嵌套模式并谈论
corner cases but corner case is an
角落案例，但角落案例是
inference make your life better when
推理可以使您的生活变得更好
they're supported so I think there'll be
他们得到了支持，所以我认为
a lot of that and I'm very excited about
很多，我为此感到非常兴奋
being able to publish the language of um
能够发布um的语言
specs more frequently what Alex said
规格更频繁Alex说了什么
about the language goes for the VM to
有关虚拟机的语言
you that the VM the VM has a lot of
您认为VM拥有很多VM
small opportunities for improvement and
改善的机会很小，
some of them are so small if we did
如果我们这样做的话，其中一些很小
everything with a grand galactic scale
一切都拥有巨大的银河规模
Big Bang feature driven engineering that
大爆炸功能驱动的工程
takes two years those little
那花了两年的时间
improvements never get in yeah but if
改善永远不会实现，但是如果
we're if we're doing things on the part
如果我们在做某件事
of the being liberated by the the
被解放的
six-month cadence is not only shipping
六个月的节奏不仅是出货
when you're ready but also being able to
当你准备好但也能够
ship something that's that's right right
运送正确的东西
size to downward somebody else yes so
尺寸缩小到其他人是的
you mentioned some of the deprecated
您提到了一些已弃用的
classes that will be removed in support
将在支持中删除的类
of entire module modules so are there
整个模块的模块，所以在那里
any others out there that have lingered
在那里徘徊的任何其他人
for years that are difficult and just
多年来艰难而公正
never went away that we should start
永不消失，我们应该开始
worrying about yeah well yes I know so
好担心，是的，我知道
in in 9 to give you a little more detail
在9中为您提供更多细节
we have deprecated all of the modules
我们已经弃用了所有模块
that contain api's that overlap with
包含与重叠的api
Java EE plus the Corbyn module so those
Java EE加上Corbyn模块，因此
are there they're a 9 they're actually
他们在那里是9他们实际上是
not resolved by default due to a really
默认情况下，由于
hairy compatibility problem but they're
多毛的兼容性问题，但它们是
there you can ask for them they work
在那里你可以要求他们工作
that's not a problem and they will be
没问题，他们会的
removed now it's a perennial question
现在删除，这是一个长期存在的问题
why don't you remove that you know those
你为什么不删除，你知道那些
three deprecated methods over in
三种不推荐使用的方法
java.awt component or those twelve
java.awt组件或那十二
deprecated methods over in this other
不推荐使用的方法
place and the answer is it's not really
的地方，答案是不是真的
worth the cost in most cases it wouldn't
在大多数情况下值得付出的代价
save very much that's that's one reason
节省很多，这就是原因之一
why why we are rather doctor deprecated
为什么我们宁愿医生弃用
er was under the leadership of dr. dr.
er在博士的领导下博士
Debra cater
黛布拉迎合
enhance the deprecation annotation in 9
增强9中的弃用注释
so it can indicate when was something
这样就可以指出什么时候
deprecated and is there an expressed
已弃用，是否有表达
intent to remove it so all those
打算删除它，所以所有这些
annoying methods in a WT will we ever
WT中的烦人方法
remove them now probably not what what's
现在删除它们可能不是什么
you know what's what's the benefit at
你知道有什么好处
the most of them just redirects from
其中大多数只是从重定向
from the old method name to the new
从旧方法名称到新方法
method name it's not like it's a huge
方法名不是很大
maintenance burden or anything else we
维护负担或其他任何我们
might be a little freer about
可能会比较自由
deprecating things piecemeal here and
零碎的东西在这里零碎
there but you know I I would I would
在那里，但你知道我会
caution you against hoping for all
提醒您不要希望所有人
deprecated methods to be removed but
不推荐使用的方法将被删除，但
that will probably never happen and
那可能永远不会发生，
since every time someone mentions
因为每次有人提到
deprecation I like to mention incubation
弃用我喜欢提到孵化
as well yes it's a dual yes since
是的，这是双重的，因为
incubation so JEP 11 is incubator
孵化，因此JEP 11是孵化器
modules and incubator module is a way of
模块和孵化器模块是一种方式
shipping an incubating feature which is
提供了一个孵化功能
basically an API that is in developments
基本上是一个正在开发的API
its package name will change should it
它的软件包名称将会更改
ever be standardized but it might in
曾经被标准化，但可能在
fact be removed and then that would also
事实上被删除，然后那也
be changing its package name because you
正在更改其软件包名称，因为您
couldn't import it anymore and the point
再也无法导入它了
is that the conception of incubating
是孵化的概念
features would be that something goes
特点是
into one of these things let's say in
这些事情之一，我们说
JDK 9 example JDK . incubator or HTTP
JDK 9示例JDK。孵化器或HTTP
clients and then it's got vector the jdk
客户，然后有矢量的JDK
dot incubator dot vector I believe if
我相信如果点孵化器点矢量
you pay close attention although that's
你要密切注意，尽管那是
not a nine might be in some future
未来可能不会有九个
release who knows which one so the the
释放谁知道哪个
conception of these incubating features
这些孵化功能的概念
that they go into a full heavyweight
他们全力以赴
3-year release and people get experience
3年发布，人们积累了经验
with it and either it it gets
用它，或者它得到
standardized or it comes out well that's
标准化或结果很好
now on a six month cadence as well so if
现在也需要六个月的节奏
you're seeing httpclient today unless
您今天看到的是httpclient，除非
you I see a lot of samples and questions
你我看到很多样本和问题
on the web about that API it's not that
在网络上有关该API的不是
it has to be definitely done or out by
它一定要完成或由
18.3 it can be later than 18.3 but it
18.3可以晚于18.3，但是
can be sooner than three years for a new
可能要不到三年才能换一个新的
API
API
has anyone thought about using the
有没有人考虑过使用
container metaphor for describing how a
容器隐喻，用于描述
JVM gets initialized in terms of not
JVM的初始化不是
only classes being loaded but objects
仅加载类，但对象
already been instantiated so that I mean
已经实例化，所以我的意思是
like we do with docker light I mean
就像我们对docker light所做的那样
having slices built upon each other I
彼此切成薄片我
mean the images right so that when I
是指图像正确，以便当我
then bring up the JVM according to that
然后根据那个调出JVM
description it has already all the
说明它已经拥有了所有
classes that's probably the easier part
类可能是更容易的部分
but the objects already insensate it if
但是如果
I had done that manually sort of you
我已经手动完成了
know container yeah we we have various
知道容器是的，我们有各种各样的
technologies that go a little bit ways
有点技术
towards that but not in the in the in
朝着那个，而不是在里
the sort of slick way that dr. that
博士的那种巧妙的方式那
docker cans layer the images on top of
泊坞窗罐将图像分层放置在
each other I mean we've had for awhile
彼此，我是说我们已经有一段时间了
now a thing called class data sharing
现在称为类数据共享的事物
one of the one of the closed features
封闭功能之一
that Oracle is going to open source this
Oracle将为此开源
application class data sharing where you
在哪里共享应用程序类数据
can you can point point the VM at your
您可以将VM指向您的
own application classes and they'll
拥有应用程序类，他们将
create a pre-baked archive that makes it
创建一个预烘焙的存档
but it makes it faster to load up those
但是它可以更快地加载那些
classes at runtime right in four years
四年内在运行时上课
we've done that for the JDK classes
我们已经为JDK类做到了
themselves with this feature you can do
自己可以使用此功能
it for your own application classes but
它为您自己的应用程序类，但
there but there's not yet a notion of
那里，但是还没有一个概念
layering another another tricky part
分层另一个棘手的部分
about layering especially with some of
关于分层，尤其是与
the other changes in nine is you know
九个其他的变化是
our ter is gone right and it's this new
我们的ter走对了，这是新的
file you know it's it's in Lib slash
文件，您知道它在Lib斜杠中
module in a format that we will not
模块的格式，我们不会
specify because it's going to change
指定，因为它将改变
frequently completely internal that file
经常完全在该文件内部
is not designed to be layered on top of
并非旨在分层
any others now it doesn't mean it
现在没有其他任何意思
couldn't be it's just that that idiom we
不可能只是那个成语
had is not one that we've that we've
拥有不是我们拥有的
thought deeply about I think it's an
深思熟虑，我认为这是一个
interesting question to ask it's also
有趣的问题也要问
it's also unclear would that really be
还不清楚这真的是
useful or in the world of docker is is a
有用的或在docker世界中是
JDK or a subset of the JDK is that a
JDK或JDK的子集是
fine enough grained unit do you really
足够细的颗粒真的吗
need to be able to layer bits of JDK S
需要能够分层JDK S
on top of each other or not I don't I
在彼此之上我不是吗
don't know
不知道
ah even like a small talk or a lisp save
啊，即使是闲聊或轻率保存
the world have that's a much harder
世界上要困难得多
problem it's honor it it's on our wish
问题，很荣幸，这是我们的愿望
list but it's very very far out there
清单，但是非常远
not far down but far out because there's
不远但很远，因为
several wishes we have to make it come
我们要实现的几个愿望
true first in order to make that happen
真正做到第一
so we solved classpath hell with modules
所以我们用模块解决了类路径地狱
I think we will eventually need to
我认为我们最终将需要
address static and it hell with
解决静态问题
something like what you're talking about
就像你在说什么
and so we have some early days ideas
所以我们有一些早期的想法
about this but we we have to crawl
关于这个，但我们必须抓取
before we can fly so if I can ask can we
在我们可以飞之前，如果我能问我们可以
have the microphone passed back after
麦克风传回后
your question is done because otherwise
您的问题已完成，因为否则
only the people in this section will
只有本节中的人会
actually get to ask any questions and
真正开始问任何问题，
that doesn't seem fair so here's a
这似乎不公平，所以这是一个
question from from Twitter um have the
来自Twitter的问题um有
four of us considered forming a
我们四个人考虑组成一个
barbershop quartet you wouldn't want to
理发店四重奏，你不想
hear that probably not it's timely that
听到可能不是及时
you brought up modules because that was
您提出了模块，因为那是
the scope of my of my question noting
我的问题范围
that G saw and modules go back with jsr
G锯和模块与jsr一起使用
to 77 to about 12 years so the concept
到77至12年左右
is old enough to be going to junior high
年纪大到可以升入初中
no sorry the concept of modules goes
不对，模块的概念消失了
back to a classic 1971 or 72 paper by
回到经典的1971或72
David Lords Parnas my apology yes not is
David Lords Parnas我的道歉是不是
not a new idea
不是一个新主意
I meant with respect to Java that I am
我的意思是关于Java
rightly put in my place if it's taken
如果采取了正确的放置在我的位置
that amount of time for expert groups
专家组花费的时间
and Oracle to have done this what hope
和Oracle做到了这一希望
is there for the rest of us in
在我们其余的人那里
modularizing our legacy code bases
模块化我们的旧代码库
abandon all hope ye who enter here
放弃所有希望你们进入这里的人
it's it's it's it's not that bad so this
是的，不是那么糟糕，所以这
was a a long-running project for many
对于许多人来说，这是一个长期运行的项目
many different reasons and guess what a
许多不同的原因，你猜怎么着
lot of them were not technical I mean
其中很多不是技术性的
technically it was it was tough didn't
从技术上讲这很艰难
you no doubt about that trying to fit a
您毫无疑问地尝试适合
module system into an existing platform
将模块系统集成到现有平台中
while maintaining as much compatibility
同时保持尽可能多的兼容性
as we possibly could without degrading
尽可能不降级
performance it was it was quite
性能是相当
difficult but there were also political
困难，但也有政治
and even business issues you may
甚至是您可能遇到的业务问题
remember when I first started talking
记得当我第一次开始说话
about modules working on models publicly
关于模块在模型上公开工作
that was in 2009 and my employer was a
那是在2009年，我的雇主是
different company you know son son son
你知道不同的公司儿子儿子儿子
was acquired time was lost that's what
被获取的时间浪费了，那是什么
happens in corporate acquisitions and
发生在企业收购和
everything and there was nobody else in
一切，没有其他人在
the wider world when you're working on
在工作时，更广阔的世界
that particular set a problem so things
那个特别设置了一个问题，所以事情
did sorry stall for a while the whole
抱歉让整个摊子停了一会儿
space of module systems is also one that
模块系统的空间也是
is politically challenging because there
政治上的挑战，因为那里
are solutions that overlap with what
是与什么重叠的解决方案
jigsaw does and do a bunch of fancier
拼图做和做很多鸽友
things too which you know many many
你也知道很多事情
people think oh well you you know you
人们认为哦，你知道你
think cut probably the most frequently
认为削减可能是最频繁的
asked question oh just use OSGi right
问的问题哦，只使用OSGi对吧
well just just use it just use it you
好吧，就用吧，就用吧
know you know and I won't repeat them
知道你知道，我不再重复
here but they're play there are many
在这里，但他们在玩，有很多
strong technical reasons why that was
有力的技术原因
not the right answer
不正确的答案
nonetheless it created a political
尽管如此，它创造了政治上的
environment in you know in the wider
您所了解的环境更广泛
Java community where there's a lot of
Java社区，那里有很多
tension and you know those of us working
紧张，你知道我们当中的那些人
on jigsaw I had to work hard to try to
在拼图上，我不得不努力尝试
defuse those tensions and you know some
化解那些紧张局势，你知道一些
people in the in the other module system
其他模块系统中的人员
communities neo also helped to to
新社区也帮助
understand okay there is common ground
了解好，有共同点
but there are also different problems
但也有不同的问题
being solved here it's okay for there to
在这里解决就可以了
be one more than one modularity solution
成为一种以上的模块化解决方案
in in the java technology ecosphere
在Java技术生态圈中
that's that that's actually not a bad
那实际上并不是一件坏事
thing so yeah it took a long time I you
是的，所以我花了很长时间
know sometimes I reflect back on this
知道有时候我会反思
and
和
I'm kind of jealous of my colleagues
我有点嫉妒我的同事
because usually what they do is not
因为通常他们做的不是
nearly as fraught with politics you know
几乎充满了政治知识
you know pattern matching in in the java
你知道java中的模式匹配
programming language is somebody gonna
编程语言会有人
kvetch and cry that oh i wrote a library
跪求哭泣，哦，我写了一个图书馆
five years ago that does something
五年前那做某事
vaguely like this you should just use
像这样模糊地应该使用
that well
那好
unlikely so anyway sorry a bit of a
不太可能，所以无论如何对不起
long-winded answer it's all right mark
answer不休的答案，这是正确的标记
keep standing there please I make a
一直站在那里，请
comment about the ridiculously broad
关于荒谬的评论
surface of the Java SE ap is it's true
Java SE ap的表面是真的
that jsr 277 starts didn't sketched out
的jsr 277开始并没有勾勒出来
in 2005 but that was not modular that
在2005年，但是那不是模块化的
was not modularization of the java
不是Java的模块化
platform that was an abstract module
一个抽象模块的平台
system you say well okay Oh 2008 and
系统，你说的很好，哦，2008年，
then you lose some time because of the
那么你会因为
Sun Oracle thing okay well the 2010 it
Sun Oracle 2010还可以吗
still years and years and years the
仍年复一年
module grab you know producing you know
模块抢你知道产生你知道
first of all visualizing visualizing the
首先可视化
modules in your application is a fairly
您的应用程序中的模块是一个相当
straightforward thing right there are
直截了当的东西
tools to help with that you can sketch
可以帮助您素描的工具
out a basic graph hey put put put each
出一个基本图嘿放放每个
jar into one module and write the
将Jar放入一个模块中，然后将
dependencies and you're done you're done
依赖关系，你做完了
here's the thing about the JDK first of
这是关于JDK的第一件事
all we kept discovering little surfaces
我们一直在发现小小的表面
that were not part of the SE API but
那不是SE API的一部分，但是
that were as if they were part of the SE
就好像它们是SE的一部分一样
API in AWT in xml and you have to then
XML中的AWT中的API，然后您必须
sit through and say so hanging this has
坐着说，所以挂这个有
never been documented as part of SE but
从未被记录为SE的一部分，但
it's been exposed as if it has been so
它已经被暴露出来
what should we do and that's it's
我们应该怎么做，就是这样
neither a technical question nor is it
既不是技术问题，也不是
really political or business but it is a
真正的政治或商业，但这是一个
policy question then there's this whole
政策问题，然后是整个
encapsulation story of it's dead it's
封装的故事，它已经死了
obvious what the public protocol of the
显而易见的是，
Java based module is it's the java.lang
基于Java的模块是java.lang
package in the java io package etc etc
封装在java io包等中
some misko was hived off to the side so
一些杂子被扔到一边，所以
that was a whole policy decision in
那是整个政策的决定
itself right the sunless gun safe is
本身就是没阳光的枪支保险柜
still there and it's in its own module
仍然在那里，它在自己的模块中
it's called JDK unsupported I remember
我记得它被称为JDK不支持
an entire meeting about naming that
关于命名的整个会议
module
模组
I remember multiple meetings about
我记得有多次关于
naming which by the way eventually will
命名方式最终将
go away right about about so this is
大约消失，所以这是
Judy unsupported that sounds like a
朱迪不受支持，听起来像是
dangerous term for an enterprise vendor
企业供应商的危险术语
to be putting out in everybody's runtime
投入到每个人的运行时中
images when we're selling support for
我们出售支持时的图片
the JDK but there's an unsupported
JDK，但是有一个不受支持的
module in there that kind of thing so
模块在那里
okay so you eventually fine you've got
好吧，所以你最终会好起来的
you've got all these exports from Java
您已经从Java获得了所有这些导出
base you've got the legacy some stuff
基地你有一些遗产
over in Suraj it account supported oh
在Suraj中它支持帐户哦
but then it turns out that all of the
但事实证明，所有
libraries are using protected asset
图书馆正在使用受保护的资产
accessible on protected methods of
可通过以下受保护的方法访问
official API s in other words they're
换句话说，它们是官方API
invoking them in an in a in an
在a in in中调用它们
inappropriate manner
不适当的方式
I think you've defined class typically
我认为您通常已经定义了课程
finalized and so you say huh and frankly
定案，所以你坦白地说
that is not a problem you're gonna have
那不是你要解决的问题
for your library or for your code base
用于您的库或代码库
and now you've got to come up with a
现在您必须提出一个
policy for what should we allow and then
我们应该允许什么的政策，然后
I mean that that alone took most of this
我的意思是，仅此一项就占了大部分
year about how open do we want and this
关于我们想要多开放的一年
is before the deprecated for removal
在不建议移除之前
stuff for EE and figuring that out so
EE的东西，并弄清楚
all of these it's the it's managing this
所有这些都是它的管理
surface area that's why when we talk
这就是为什么当我们说话时
about modules and it is it seems like
关于模块，这似乎是
okay there's a graph that's grades but
好吧，有一张图是成绩，但
what those things are exporting versus
这些东西正在输出与
not exporting ie what what we want you
不出口，即我们想要什么
to care about versus what you really
在乎与你真正的相处
mustn't care about it's it's it's this
不必在意它是因为
weird it's not programming it's not
很奇怪，这不是编程，不是
architecture it's but it's something
建筑，但这是某种东西
that only really only the JDK has to go
只有JDK才需要
through it's empirical to right
通过正确的经验
yes it's yeah we weeded met many many
是的，是的，我们除草遇到了很多
analyses of like a dump of made maven
分析像人造粪堆
central to figure things out
解决问题的中心
yeah does existing code use this or not
是的，现有代码是否使用此代码
what you actually mentioned in the key
您在钥匙中实际提到的内容
nodes that the recommended naming
建议命名的节点
convention for modules is is reverse DNS
模块的约定是反向DNS
based or you didn't say this but I'm
基于，或者你没有说这个，但是我
pretty sure this is our policy on based
很确定这是我们基于
on the principle package in the module
关于模块中的基本包装
well primary primarily reverse DNS
主要主要是反向DNS
principal package when that makes sense
主体包什么时候有意义
so I would so-so resident that in itself
所以我会自己就这样
was a huge debate that a huge debate
一场激烈的辩论
based on the see I believe Brian Fox is
基于我认为Brian Fox是
Brian Fox here I don't know what he
Brian Fox在这里，我不知道他是什么
looks like
看起来像
the CEO of source OCT oh if SonoSite
来源OCT的首席执行官哦，如果SonoSite
gave a whole bunch of input about names
提供了大量有关名称的输入
of maven artifacts and a or her we
专家文物和我们
haven't even mentioned automatic modules
甚至都没有提到自动模块
via thing in itself but bear in mind a
通过事物本身，但要记住一个
big feature of the module system is that
模块系统的最大特点是
it supports code that isn't in modules I
它支持不在模块中的代码
challenge you to find another module
挑战您寻找另一个模块
system that supports that you will not
支持您不会的系统
find one you can take non modular code
找到一个可以采用非模块化代码的代码
and treat as if it is modules it will
并视其为模块将
get a name it will get resolved there
得到一个名字，它将在那里解决
will be an API for those things you can
将是您可以使用的API
reflect on them it goes on and on and on
反思他们不断
and on and on didn't see that anywhere
并不断在任何地方都看不到
else don't see it in jboss modules don't
否则在jboss模块中看不到
see it in OSGi so that that migration
在OSGi中看到它，以便进行迁移
story also took a long time
故事也花了很长时间
very quick
很快
yeah just very quick so there's a lot of
是的，非常快，所以有很多
32-bit systems out there still is Oracle
Oracle仍然存在32位系统
for the long run for that one can only
从长远来看，那只能
do so many things at a time okay
一次做很多事情好吗
I was asking after 20 years of oh sorry
我问了20年后，对不起
I was gonna try to answer this
我本来想回答这个
gentleman's question first sorry okay
先生的问题首先对不起
yeah so we did we did shape the ship
是的，所以我们做到了，我们确实做了船的形状
32-bit builds of the JDK nine early
JDK的32位构建九个早期
access releases and when we shipped GA
访问版本以及我们运送GA的时间
we where we in this case is Oracle we
我们在这种情况下是Oracle我们
did not ship 32-bit builds this was a
没有交付32位版本，这是一个
decision you know driven by but you know
你知道的决定，但你知道
by basically resource issues does it
基本上是资源问题
there's only so only so much we can do
我们只能做的只有这么多
for the types of developers that
针对那种类型的开发商
Oracle's most most interested in
甲骨文最感兴趣的
enabling 32-bits not that interesting
启用32位不是那么有趣
but you know all the source code is
但是你知道所有的源代码是
still there you know you can you can
仍然在那里，你知道你可以
build it I'm sure other vendors will
建立它，我相信其他供应商会
ship 32-bit builds and and that's part
交付32位版本，这是其中的一部分
of what open JDK is all about Oracle
关于Oracle的JDK开放
doesn't have to do everything yeah you
不必做所有的事情，是的，你
know we talked about moving faster right
知道我们谈论过更快地前进
you know and part of moving faster is
你知道，加快步伐的一部分是
doing less right and and so shipping
没做正确的事情，所以运输
binary is on fifty six platforms is
二进制是在五十六个平台上
something that makes it harder to move
很难移动的东西
faster and so perhaps you know it is a
更快，所以也许您知道这是一个
better trade off to ship binaries and
更好地权衡以运输二进制文件和
and support the platforms that cover you
并支持覆盖您的平台
know ninety-eight percent of the user
知道百分之九十八的用户
base so that those resources can be used
基础，以便可以使用这些资源
on you know more forward-looking things
在你身上知道更多前瞻性的东西
and just
而只是
I'm gonna throw something out there for
我要去那里扔东西
your amusement that that's related to
与您有关的娱乐
old platforms because this is the kind
旧平台，因为这是那种
of thing that someone who wants to run
想跑的人
on an older on X people want to do no
在X上较年长的人不愿意
one has yet noticed that Java C in
一个人尚未注意到Java C
jeddah k9 when when you specify - source
吉达k9，当您指定时-源
and - target who specifies source and
以及-谁指定来源和
target when they invoke their compiler
他们调用编译器时的目标
some have frankly not many people but
坦率地说，有些人不是很多，但是
some people did ek9 you can do nine
有人做了ek9你可以做到九
eight seven and six you can't do any
八七六，你什么也做不了
earlier than that that's why NetBeans
早于此，这就是NetBeans的原因
doesn't compile on JDK nine because if
无法在JDK 9上编译，因为如果
you have a legacy system that has got
你有一个遗留系统
source one for built into all of the ant
所有蚂蚁的内置源
files because that's just where you are
文件，因为那正是您的位置
you're on X pianist in an environment
您正在环境中使用X钢琴家
where they're not upgrading that's
他们没有升级的地方
another compatibility surface of that
另一个兼容性表面
you will be affected by JDK nine but it
您将受到JDK 9的影响，但是
is clearly to everyone's benefit that
显然对所有人都有好处
the Java C internals doesn't have to
Java C内部不必
drag around 1997 era code that supports
拖延支持的1997年时代代码
1:1 for example the ability to assume
例如1：1的假设能力
that all code that is being compiled
所有正在编译的代码
this from the era of generics means you
这来自仿制药时代
would interpret a type name as a raw
会将类型名称解释为原始
type rather than as neither a row type
类型而不是既不是行类型
nor generics because that's how it
也没有泛型，因为这就是
wasn't one two okay third time after 20
20点后第三次不是一两个还好
years of doing optimizations in JVM do
多年在JVM中进行优化的过程
you think that everything that is left
你认为剩下的一切
is micro optimizations or do you really
是微优化还是您真的
believe it that 9 is going to put on
相信9会穿上
solid ground to maybe do some big chance
可能会有很大机会的坚实基础
of optimizing the JVM are you talking
您正在谈论优化JVM
about the optimization code quality from
关于优化代码质量的信息
the JIT yeah okay well we have a nice
JIT是的，好的，我们有一个不错的选择
little group of JIT engineers that work
一小组工作的JIT工程师
on stuff like that and they are they are
在这样的东西上，他们是
driven by whatever new whatever new
由新事物驱动
initiatives were doing such as value
倡议正在做诸如价值
types they're also driven by our sense
他们也受我们的意识驱动
according to our best information as to
根据我们的最佳信息
the experience of customers and and what
客户的经验以及什么
what what loops they're failing to
他们失败了什么循环
optimize and
优化和
you know so we're always making small if
你知道吗，如果
you look at the changelog on the on the
您可以查看上的更新日志
JIT portion of hotspot you'll see a lot
热点的JIT部分，您会看到很多
of small ad hoc optimization changes
临时优化更改的数量
though there's an intrinsic we need here
虽然这里有内在的需要
or probably the most dramatic stuff in
或可能是最戏剧性的东西
the nine era would that that is new
九个时代会是新的吗
would be support for the newer Intel
将支持较新的英特尔
hardware as well as other there's other
硬件以及其他
chips out there too that we support but
我们也支持那里的筹码，但
you know Intel is what we're
你知道英特尔就是我们
concentrating on but you'll see you'll
专心，但是你会看到你会
see more frequent success of
看到更频繁的成功
vectorization although for reasons
矢量化，尽管出于某些原因
already explained in previous session we
在上一届会议上我们已经解释过了
don't put all of our eggs in the auto
不要把我们所有的鸡蛋都放在汽车上
vectorization basket we want explicit
我们要明确的向量化篮
vectorization also yeah there's probably
向量化也可以
a large slide with tiny print of all the
一张大型幻灯片，上面印有所有
small compiler changes we've made and is
我们对编译器进行的小更改是
that does it answer your question yes I
那能回答你的问题吗
think John's being a little modest here
认为约翰在这里有点谦虚
so if I could paraphrase the question
所以我可以解释一下这个问题
boy you know the JVM has done amazing
男孩，您知道JVM做得很棒
optimizations over the last 20 years is
最近20年的优化是
there anything left to do I think that
我还有什么要做的
is the essence of your question and oh
是您问题的实质，哦
my god yes right so yes we've done
我的上帝是的，所以是的，我们已经完成了
amazing things over the last it's the
最后令人惊奇的事情是
last 20 years and there is so much left
最近20年，还有很多
to do you know there's there's big
你知道那里有很多
things you know what John was talking
你知道约翰在说什么
about but both auto vectorization and
关于但自动向量化和
you know manual vectorization there is
你知道有手动矢量化
better multi-threaded performance better
更好的多线程性能
memory latency optimizing object layout
内存延迟优化对象布局
for the memory you know characteristics
您知道的记忆特征
of today's systems hardware is
今天的系统硬件是
constantly evolving the software has to
不断发展的软件必须
you know has to have some awareness of
你知道必须有一些意识
what the hardware's gonna do so that we
硬件将要做什么，以便我们
can generate optimal code so there is no
可以生成最佳代码，所以没有
shortage of really cool things to work
缺乏真正酷的工作
on it I'll put in a note here about
关于这一点，我将在此处写下有关
project metropolis the the increase in
大都市项目的增加
in in nimbleness that we're getting from
我们从中得到的敏捷
the faster cadence will be mirrored I
更快的节奏将被反映
hope in the not-too-distant future by a
希望在不久的将来
succession of technologies from the
技术的继承
server compiler C to jet which is
服务器编译器C喷射
written in C++ and is about 15 years old
用C ++编写，已有15年历史
and the
和
and a new a new jet probably based on
和一架新的新飞机可能基于
the Gras technology which has been under
Gras技术已经在
continuous development for for many
许多人的持续发展
years now and is beginning to rival on
多年，并开始在
some metrics the c2 jet so the next step
一些指标C2喷气机，所以下一步
for us after having played with t for
在与äôt一起玩过之后
the JDK 9 timeframe is to begin applying
JDK 9时间表将开始应用
t to the two Graul itself and then
对两个Graul本身，然后
bundling that into the hotspot VM and
将其捆绑到热点VM中
trying that code out to see how it goes
尝试该代码，看看它如何进行
that is not why don't you just use Gras
那不是为什么你不只是使用Gras
instead of c2 that is not one of those
而不是c2就是其中之一
sorts of problems this is a multi-year
这是一个多年的问题
better part of a decade succession
十年接班的大部分时间
problem kind of like modules and and yes
问题有点像模块，是的
we can do it with the six month cadence
我们可以用六个月的节奏来做到这一点
bit by bit by bit and with with
一点一点地与
long-running side projects but in any
长期运行的项目，但在任何情况下
case what I hope to get to there to
案例我希望能到达那里
answer the question is a more flexible
回答问题更灵活
fluid codebase that's easier to work on
流畅的代码库，更易于使用
that's smaller simpler lighter more
越小越轻
modern than the current C++ C of nodes
比当前的C ++ C节点更现代
compiler digit that we have now instead
我们现在拥有的编译器数字
it'll be a java-based C of nodes with a
这将是基于Java的C节点
with a refreshed design and with as
具有刷新的设计和
we've found it's much easier if you're
我们发现，如果您
working with Gras which is Java based
使用基于Java的Gras
you know a Java program with annotations
您知道带有注释的Java程序
and modern stuff in it
和其中的现代东西
especially as Brian adds new modern and
特别是当Brian添加新的现代和
stuff to the language it'll be much more
语言的东西会更多
pleasant and therefore faster and safer
令人愉快的，因此更快更安全
to to add new optimizations with the
来添加新的优化
Java on Java strategy and that's what
Java on Java策略就是这样
metropolis is about and as you probably
大都市即将来临
know from the mailing lists we're just
从邮件列表中知道我们只是
beginning to boot that up alright
开始启动它好了
anybody who hasn't asked a question the
没有问过任何问题的人
mic is moving just slowly sorry
麦克风正在缓慢移动，抱歉
because because Java 9 is using the G
因为因为Java 9使用G
memory and the processor directly is it
内存和处理器直接是
possible for the programmer to hack or
程序员可能会破解或
what read viruses in the GDK 9 I'm sorry
抱歉，在GDK 9中读取了哪些病毒
I couldn't couldn't purse that speak
我不能讲那个话
more slowly maybe Oh
可能慢一点哦
because JDK 1989 we can use memory
因为JDK 1989我们可以使用内存
access directly or for the processor and
直接访问或访问处理器，以及
for the memory accidentally so is it
意外的记忆是这样
possible for the programmer to create
程序员可以创建的
viruses or such type of stuffs can you
病毒或此类物品，您可以
create virus 9 because it is using
创建病毒9，因为它正在使用
direct memory access by a direct memory
通过直接内存直接访问内存
what do you think why if the process
您如何看待这个过程
boundaries in your us OS don't work I
您的美国操作系统的边界不起作用我
suppose you could sorry what do you
假设你可以对不起你
think you'll fight direct memory access
认为您将与直接内存访问抗争
that's because I have learned just
那是因为我学到了
listen that it is using the processing
听着它正在使用处理
CPU directly in previous lectures what
CPU直接在以前的讲座中有什么
is the name of that lecture are you
那堂课的名字是你吗
thinking for handles for the vector and
想着向量的句柄和
vectors right so the old way of doing
向量正确，所以做旧的方法
vectors is either writing assembly code
向量正在编写汇编代码
in an atom statement or in a you know
在原子陈述或你知道的
dot s file or it's if you have the GCC
点的文件，或者是否有GCC
tools you you can there are a few
您可以使用的工具有一些
intrinsic sin the extended geez good new
内在的罪过
C C compiler that will let you program
CC编译器，可让您进行编程
some vector instructions and plus
一些矢量说明和加号
there's a whole header file in full of
有一个完整的头文件
intrinsics so we're doing something like
内部函数，所以我们正在做类似的事情
that but it has the Java properties of
那但它具有Java属性
safety and integrity compatibility etc I
安全性和完整性兼容性等
forgot one of yours mark and then but
忘记了你的一个标记，然后但是
the the Java vector API will let you
Java vector API可以让您
code a vector add instruction just like
编写矢量添加指令的代码，就像
today you in Java you can code an
今天，您可以使用Java编写代码
integer add instruction it's the plus
整数加法指令是加号
sign what the what Java will not let you
签署什么Java不会让你做什么
do is get bounds check
要做的是检查边界
elision that will lets you do a buffer
使您可以缓冲的省略
overflow it will not let you jump into a
溢出它不会让你跳入
data buffer there's a whole bunch of
数据缓冲区有一大堆
safety operations that you can easily
您可以轻松进行的安全操作
that are in Java you can easily override
在Java中，您可以轻松覆盖
them in C even by accident that you'll
即使在偶然的情况下，它们也会以C语言出现
never be able to override them in Java
永远无法在Java中覆盖它们
unless you use something unsafe yeah
除非你使用不安全的东西
unless you're an implementer unless
除非你是一个实施者，除非
you're an implementer of the lower
你是下层的实施者
layers of the stack and you're willing
栈的每一层，你愿意
to take their take that take that
采取他们的采取
responsibility on but most people don't
承担责任，但大多数人不承担责任
need it
需要它
whereas in C even the person writing
而在C语言中，即使是写作
hello world takes on the responsibility
你好，世界承担责任
to avoid a buffer overrun or code
避免缓冲区溢出或代码
execution out of a buffer or something
在缓冲区之类的地方执行
like that okay there was another
像那样好，还有另一个
question up here
在这里提问
can I ask my question or should I feel
我可以问我一个问题还是我应该感到
free to throw things at me if it's a
有空的话可以随意向我扔东西
stupid question but do you support
愚蠢的问题，但你支持
modulized versioning for module modules
模块模块的模块化版本控制
and watch that's a mark one
看着那是一个标记
no thanks question no modules are
不用了，谢谢，没有模块
modules are our constructs known to the
模块是我们已知的构造
language in the VM they're not artifacts
VM中的语言不是工件
it's important to keep the distinction
保持区别很重要
straight right a module you know a jar
直接在一个你知道罐子的模块上
file is an artifact it can define a
文件是一个工件，它可以定义一个
module or not but a module is kind of a
是否使用模块，但模块是一种
higher level more abstract thing there
更高层次的抽象事物
are not version numbers on them this was
不是版本号，这是
an intentional design decision I realize
我意识到的一个故意的设计决定
it's yeah we know really we know very
是的，我们知道，我们非常了解
well it's somewhat counterintuitive
好吧，这有点违反直觉
because people expect all modules to die
因为人们希望所有模块都消失
version numbers doesn't mean someday
版本号并不意味着有一天
they won't but I think they're a bunch
他们不会，但我认为他们是一群
of strong technical reasons why that's
技术原因的原因
probably never gonna be a good idea I
可能永远不会是一个好主意
think we're simple first is good so I'm
认为我们首先简单是好的，所以我
asked this on Twitter but I can ask it
在Twitter上问了这个，但我可以问
in person now so there's a lots of
现在面对面，所以有很多
languages and lots of language features
语言和许多语言功能
out there that you can draw ideas from I
在那里，你可以从我那里汲取灵感
would obviously can't pull in everything
显然无法吸收一切
in the kitchen sink how do you decide
在厨房的水槽里，你如何决定
what's appropriate for Java and have
什么适合Java并拥有
there ever been any ideas that you
曾经有过任何想法
thought were philosophically very good
在思想上认为很好
that were not appropriate for Java one
不适合Java
one answer is easy that the default
一个答案很容易，默认
answer to the why don't you just add
为什么不添加的答案
question is no all right it's not an
问题是不是很好，这不是
answer to a wide but I mean it's it is
广泛的答案，但我的意思是
it isn't it is never been a goal indeed
确实不是从来没有一个目标
it's been a contrast sort of anti going
这是一种反抗的对比
it's not a goal to add every cool
添加所有酷炫的目标不是目标
language if you try no that's that's not
语言，如果您尝试不，那不是
what you're asking but you know a very
你在问什么，但你知道
frequently we get feedback of the form
我们经常收到以下形式的反馈
oh well you know cool language X has
哦，你知道X语言很酷
feature why why don't why don't you just
精选为什么为什么不为什么不只是
add it in and the answer is as Brian
加进去，答案是布莱恩
will is capable of that's venting at
将能够发泄的能力
much greater length than I am you know
比我知道的要长得多
the answer is he is you know why don't
答案是他是你知道为什么不
you just is just
你就是
beginning of a long investigation into
开始长期调查
how does it fit with everything else is
它如何与其他一切相适应
it actually something that really needs
实际上是真正需要的东西
that everybody needs and if we do this
每个人都需要的，如果我们这样做
now what features will it prevent us
现在它将阻止我们什么功能
from doing later on because of
以后因为
compatibility so Brian you wonder why
兼容性，所以Brian您想知道为什么
don't we be really selective about how
我们不是真的有选择吗
we slowly sediment features one by one
我们慢慢地逐一沉淀特征
into our system yeah
进入我们的系统
and we have weilert we don't learn a lot
我们有韦勒特，我们学不到很多
from others I mean Scala has been a
从别人那里我是说Scala
veritable font of information about yeah
真实的信息字体，是的
that was a good idea that kind of worked
那是个好主意
out it
出来吧
yeah there's nother one over here yeah
是的，这里还有另一个
so they you know we can't possibly do
所以他们你知道我们不可能做
all of the language features that even
所有的语言功能，甚至
the ones that seem like a decent idea
那些看起来不错的主意
right so a lot of them just seem like
对，所以他们很多看起来就像
bad ideas or they seem like good ideas
坏主意或好主意
at first and until you dig at them and
首先，直到您对它们进行挖掘
then you have a list left of ones that
然后剩下一个列表，
are okay not terrible ideas and we're
没什么可怕的想法，我们
only going to implement 1% of those
只会实施其中的1％
maybe and so we have to pick and choose
也许，所以我们必须选择
very carefully and it's not like we have
非常小心，这不像我们有
a detailed scientific process it's a
详细的科学过程是
very subjective thing where we look we
我们看起来很主观的东西
you know we look at candidates and we
你知道我们看着候选人，我们
say what is the what's the
说什么是什么
thrust-to-weight ratio here right what
这里的推重比正确
is it what is it foreclose on what does
这是什么，它阻止了什么
it enable what does it encourage and how
它启用了它鼓励什么以及如何
much is that worth compared to our
与我们相比，这值得多少
limited budget for adding complexity of
有限的预算增加了复杂性
the language and again totally
语言，再一次
subjective you know but we try to we try
主观你知道，但我们尝试我们尝试
to add things that have that build on
添加有基础的东西
existing concepts rather than add new
现有概念，而不是添加新概念
concepts we try to you know add things
我们尝试让您知道的概念会增加一些东西
that have a lot of leverage obviously
具有明显的杠杆作用
something like lambda has a huge amount
诸如lambda之类的东西数量巨大
of leverage much more so than you know a
的杠杆作用远不止您所知道的
lot of other candidate language features
许多其他候选语言功能
but in the end it's a fairly subjective
但最后这是一个相当主观的
process that involves saying gee that
涉及说gee的过程
sounds nice but no to an awful lot of
听起来不错，但绝大部分都没有
things so that when something really
事情，这样当真正
good comes along we
好的伴随着我们
the ability to do it for a long time I
我有很长一段时间做这项工作的能力
thought collection literals were sort of
认为收集字面量有点
a no-brainer but eventually I was
毫无疑问，但最终我还是
convinced otherwise it's in a different
确信它是另外一个
language maybe they're a great idea
语言也许是个好主意
there's there are so many features that
有这么多的功能
are just so much more complicated than
比这复杂得多
they look and then it just becomes a
他们看起来，然后就变成了
matter of how much of our complexity
我们有多复杂
budget do we want to spend on that
我们想在这方面花费预算吗
versus something else all right I think
与其他东西没关系我认为
we're out of time so thank you very much
我们没时间了，非常感谢
for your questions
您的问题
[Applause]
[掌声]